<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Decompressing | History</title>
    <link>https://thomaswestland.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Decompressing | History</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 | Follow on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mgjohansen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mgjohansen/hucore.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hucore theme&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; ♥</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thomaswestland.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How unequal was the federation of French West Africa?</title>
      <link>https://thomaswestland.github.io/post/how-poor-were-the-sahelian-colonies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaswestland.github.io/post/how-poor-were-the-sahelian-colonies/</guid>
      <description>When the French parliament, including colonial representatives, was discussing the framework of a new relationship between French Africa and the metropole, a slight plaintive note could be detected in the contributions of the representatives of Côte d&amp;rsquo;Ivoire and Gabon. Respectively, these colonies were the largest economies of the federations of French West Africa (Afrique occidentale française, or AOF) and French Equatorial Africa (Afrique équatoriale française, or AEF). The white Ivorian planter Gaston Lagarosse said:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinochet&#39;s inequality miracle</title>
      <link>https://thomaswestland.github.io/post/pinochet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaswestland.github.io/post/pinochet/</guid>
      <description>Economists don&amp;rsquo;t agree about the economics of dictatorships: some claim that the lack of checks on the executive and the widespread repression of political voice provide an institutional framework encouraging rent-seeking and stifling growth, whereas others think that it is precisely the lack of political accountability to the electorate that allows for economic policies that make technical sense and are conducive to growth but would not attain political consensus. Economic historians, whose job description allows them to focus on cases rather than on general rules, can point to examples supporting both theses (or neither).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Decompressing History</title>
      <link>https://thomaswestland.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaswestland.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Emiliano Travieso is a PhD student in economic history at King&amp;rsquo;s College, Cambridge. He works on the economic history of the River Plate in the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries; he is also interested in ______
Tom Westland is a PhD student in economic history at Sidney Sussex College, Cambridge. His current work centres on French West Africa, and in particular Senegal in the colonial and post-independence periods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>